Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adapted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: Unfortunate Love
I can cut a thousand strands of hair
but I cannot sever the tangled threads of my mind.
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For lovers caught in eternal time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For lovers caught in eternal time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Consort Fleur, what is the matter with you?
Why would you spoil the mood on such a joyous day?
It's not that I harbor grievances against anyone.
Seeing Lady Sourire perform "Dance of the Startled Swan"
deeply touched me in my heart of hearts,
and I slipped on decorum.
You had not entered the family
when Empress Première performed the "Startled Swan."
Why are you emotional about the dance today?
I've been idling away my days reading poetry,
I stumbled upon "Lament from the East Tower" by Consort Mei.
Her poem filled me with dread.
Consort Mei composed "Dance of the Startled Swan"
when she was in high favor with Emperor Xuanzong.
She wrote this poem during the time she was confined to Shangyang Palace.
The "Startled Swan" today brought my mind to her "Lament from the East Tower."
I can't refrain from feeling sad for Consort Mei.
You've never shown much interest in poetry before.
Why have you become fond of reading poems?
I heard that poetry and literature can enlighten untutored minds.
Devoid of talent and virtue,
I will not have the face to serve Your Majesty
if I don't cultivate my character.
Since you sympathize with the poem,
why not share your thoughts with us?
“Your fond words said
your love would bind us inseparably.”
"It’ll endure as the sun and the moon," you vowed,
"it’ll abide as mountains and seas."
“How she [Yang Guifei, another consort]
seethed with wrathful jealousy.”
“She deprived me of your love,
banishing me into this forlorn tower.”
“No more can I reach the bliss of yesteryears;
in dreams, I see only a hazy memory.”
Every time I read these lines,
I am deeply saddened by Consort Mei's
love and longing for her husband.
Your Majesty, the matter concerning Consort Fleur
is a family affair within your harem.
I dare not comment on it.
But Her Highness hasn't committed
any serious wrongs while serving Your Majesty all these years.
If there was something unthoughtful in her service,
I hope Your Majesty can forgive Her Highness
considering her many years of dedicated service.
Consort Fleur,
it must have been hard on you.
Your residence in the Summer Palace is quite remote.
I'll visit you more often when I have the time.
I thank Your Majesty.
Cao, I am curious to know...
The slip with "Dance of the Startled Swan" written on it
was hidden in your sleeve, wasn't it?
So my dance was not destined, but orchestrated to happen.
I must thank you for the effort.
Sourire, what are you talking about?
I do not understand.
Your acute mind must understand that
without "Startled Swan," "Lament from the East Tower"
would not have been written.
While Consort Mei's heart-rending poem
failed to rekindle the love of Emperor Xuanzong,
Her Highness Consort Fleur moved His Majesty deeply.
Consort Mei's unrestful soul
must be so appreciative of your painstaking effort.
It is whatever you say, Sourire.
My tongue lacks the eloquence to vindicate myself.
Perhaps you should spend all your free time
taking care of Lady Vertu's pregnancy.
After all, that's His Majesty's prime concern.
By all means.
We exerted so much effort trying to bring her down,
only to watch her rise up again.
I can't accept this!
Meizhuang, you know this.
Her rising is expected.
It's always just a matter of time.
I'm just afraid that our life will become difficult again.
With this sweetheart in your belly,
there's nothing we should worry about.
Don't let anything upset you.
Your pregnancy matters the most.
It's only been one month.
We don't even know if it's a boy or a girl.
Regardless, they will always be our dearest baby.
Dear baby, please tell your mother to stop feeling upset.
Stop talking nonsense.
What happened today will be more of a headache
to the Empress than to us.
Let's not fret when Her Majesty doesn't.
You are right.
But I couldn't help feeling worried when you were dancing.
I knew that you could dance well.
But I never expected it would be an offense
either way - dancing, or not.
I got by with sheer luck.
But we can never be too careful given
Lady Cao's deep cunning and guile.
No matter how she tried to harm you,
you are shielded by His Majesty's favor.
But why were you hiding your talents from His Majesty?
If she had seen your skills beforehand,
she wouldn't have plotted this against you.
Fortunately, they are not aware of my strengths and shortcomings.
Otherwise, they would be even bolder in their plots.
Lady Sourire, His Majesty invites you to appreciate
his newly collected poems at the Governance Hall.
Go immediately. Don't make His Majesty wait.
I'll go now.
Mr Su.
Peace to Lady Sourire.
His Majesty is currently in a meeting with some officials.
I hope you won't mind waiting here for a while, My Lady.
Certainly.
Your Majesty, considering the ongoing wars in the northwest,
the service of Consort Fleur's brother
Nian Gengyao is crucial to the state.
I hope Your Majesty will reconsider.
At this juncture, a decision regarding court appointments should be expedient.
Your Majesty's forgiveness of Consort Fleur
will also lift military morale.
I understand. You can leave now.
Peace to My Lady.
My Lady, please.
Your Majesty, Lady Sourire is here.
I bow before Your Majesty.
Peace and grace to Your Majesty.
I have a headache. I can use a massage from you.
Yes.
Is something troubling Your Majesty?
How do you know?
Despite jasmine flowers being placed in the chamber,
I can still detect the scent of menthol.
I know Your Majesty applies menthol
when something is bothering you.
You are always attentive to my mind.
Take a guess at what is bothering me.
Your Majesty is concerned with everything under Heaven.
It must be some trouble at court.
You are not wrong.
But the harem falls under Heaven as well,
and it too gives me trouble.
It has been hard on Her Majesty the Empress
to single-handedly manage all the affairs in the harem.
It is time someone share her burden.
What do you think?
Consort Fleur has always assisted
Her Majesty with palace affairs.
Whatever happened was the mistake of Concubine Beauté.
Consort Fleur was not necessarily involved.
Her Majesty the Empress Dowager was just dissatisfied
over Consort Fleur being a little overbearing.
I believe Her Highness has learned a lesson.
But Consort Fleur....
That will make you feel aggrieved.
But don't worry, I'll protect you from any harm.
I will never feel aggrieved over anything
if it's for Your Majesty.
What a rare day today!
Even State Prince Dun spoke up for Your Highness.
He has always been a haughty man,
not even respectful towards His Majesty.
He's entitled to feel superior.
His mother, Noble Consort Wenxi,
is the younger sister of Empress Xiaozhaoren,
while the current Empress Dowager was merely
preceptor maid to Empress Xiaozhaoren.
After the battle for the throne among the nine lords,
although State Prince Dun's associates
Lords VIII, IV, and XIV were banished,
he managed to retain the title of State Prince.
But he cannot swallow his anger
over His Majesty's rise to the throne.
Then why would he help Your Highness?
He was not helping me.
He was "pushing the boat along the current"
to earn favor from my brother.
Great General Nian?
Prince Dun was highly ranked among his brothers
and worked with my brother on affairs in Qinghai Province.
Perhaps he did it for old times' sake.
For whatever reason, I'm happy as long as
Your Highness regains His Majesty's favor.
Is the dress ready?
It is, Your Highness.
His Majesty likes seeing Your Highness in red.
- Then hurry and help me get changed.
- Yes, Your Highness.
I must not make His Majesty wait.
Your Majesty had a long day.
You should rest early.
All the smiling I put on today
has made my face sore.
On such an occasion, Your Majesty had to
wear a smile regardless of your feelings.
It must be hard on Your Majesty.
But an empress must never say she's tired.
If those who covet my throne ever find
my power weaker than my will,
they will "skin and eat me alive".
Your Majesty is right.
Consort Fleur today... what a small woman to have gotten her way.
It disgusted me.
But she did not disgust His Majesty.
Only, I couldn't help thinking of my son Honghui,
on the ceremony of his first birthday.
If the First Prince were still with us ...
If Honghui were with us,
he would have grown taller than the Third Prince,
and more handsome.
And much smarter than the Third Prince.
Indeed.
Honghui began to read characters
when he was only two years old.
The Third Prince has nothing that compares.
Your Majesty is in your prime.
You will certainly have one more prince.
I'm past forty years of age,
not suitable for pregnancy anymore.
And after my sister died,
His Majesty never treated me the same way.
I know the condition of my health.
I'm afraid I'll never be able to.
Even though His Majesty doesn't say so,
he has a lot of respect for Your Majesty in his heart.
when a woman does not have her husband's love,
what is the use of his respect?
You've been through all these years with me.
How do you think His Majesty has treated me
compared to how he treated my sister?
Your Majesty, before Empress Première entered
the family, His Majesty treated you extremely well.
His Majesty never treated me
as well as he treated my sister.
And the Empress Dowager too.
After all, I am the daughter of a secondary wife
while my sister was of a primary wife.
If my son Honghui were with us,
he would have been the eldest son and of a primary wife.
What a distinguished status he would have.
When Honghui was dying,
it was raining just like this.
Autumn,
my migraine is piercing right now.
Your Majesty...
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
My Lady, how was your appetite the last two days?
Do you still feel nauseous?
It's strange.
I haven't felt nauseous lately.
But my stomach aches and feels cold.
I wonder what the reason is.
My Lady, you will continue to feel at ease
as you have been taking the prenatal tonics.
As for the stomach pain...
it is normal at one month of pregnancy.
I feel reassured hearing you say that.
I thought the pregnancy symptoms
would be strong in the first month.
Nay. You are in good health, My Lady.
You would not have such symptoms.
I believe you will give birth to a
healthy prince for His Majesty.
I hope I fulfill your auspicious words.
- Lunar.
- Yes.
Grant Dr. Liu some of the hawthorn cakes my father sent.
Thank you, My Lady.
The hawthorn cakes must be
made by Qishunzhai Bakery.
Qishunzhai was closed the year before last.
Dr. Liu, you were transferred to the palace this year.
Why didn't you know?
I always think of Qishunzhai when I miss home.
It feels as if the bakery should still be there.
I apologize for my slip of the tongue.
You must be missing home a lot.
I will have Lunar send you more if you like.
I thank My Lady in advance.
- Poria.
- Yes.
- See Dr. Liu out.
This way please, Dr. Liu.
I bow to thank My Lady.
Please take a break, My Lady.
Don't strain your eyes.
This one is almost done.
I will finish it.
There's no hurry, My Lady.
Lady Vertu is just one month into her pregnancy.
You have eight more months to finish the bib.
I must finish this as soon as possible.
If Meizhuang likes it, I will make a few more.
You have no idea how fast a baby grows.
They outgrow their clothes in no time.
It's not like you've had children of your own.
Growing up, I watched my mother
do needlework for the concubines' children.
That is how I have the knowledge.
I'm sorry to have triggered
your sad memories, My Lady.
I will take any punishment.
Please rise.
Why would I punish you?
But I wonder how my mother has been.
She must be so honored
that you have entered the palace.
I'm just a neglected Companion.
His Majesty might not even remember who I am.
The dragon will have to stay where it is
before having a chance to soar.
My Lady, terrible news.
What happened?
Mr. An had an accident.
My Lady.
My sisters.
My sisters, help me!
- Longrong, what happened?
- Rise. Take it easy.
My father is in jail!
How did that happen all of a sudden?
I received a letter from home saying
while my father assisted the magistrate -
Jiang Wenqing -
transferring army provisions to the Northwest,
enemy troops attacked them halfway and robbed the provisions.
Jiang Wenqing escaped and stole lots of money.
His Majesty, shaking with rage,
decreed my father's arrest along with Jiang Wenqing.
I don't know if he will live or not.
Given such fierce anger I'm afraid His Majesty
will sentence my father to death!
Did you confirm your father wasn't involved at all?
I am sure!
My father has always been cautious in his dealings.
He would never involve himself in what Jiang Wenqing did.
Don't cry, Lingrong.
There's no conclusion to this matter yet.
We must think of a solution.
Exactly.
I understand that anything concerning
the military is of great consequence.
I'm afraid the odds are more ominous than propitious.
We will definitely try to speak to His Majesty on your behalf.
It's just that... we are not allowed
to pass comments on state affairs.
You're right.
There's no need to disturb His Majesty.
In fact, Meizhuang can help me.
Me?
The incident happened within the jurisdiction of Jizhou.
Your father, as the region's Commander,
will be the interrogator.
- Meizhuang, I beg of you to help my father.
- Please stand.
I will see what I can do.
I need to think ...
Please have mercy on my father.
A letter from you will be enough to save his life.
Of course, don't worry.
But I must request an audience with His Majesty
and sound out his opinion.
Thank you, Meizhuang!
I'm eternally grateful for your help.
Lingrong, don't cry.
Aiyo, Lady Vertu...
What brought you here carrying the child?
Be careful not to be affected by the heat.
Is His Majesty inside?
Yes, but he's with Zhang Tingyu and General Longkodo.
I'm afraid you'll have to wait for a while, My Lady.
Why is General Longkodo here?
An accident happened to the
army provisions for the Northwest.
His Majesty is outraged about it.
Does that involve Companion An's father?
That, I have no idea.
All I know is that His Majesty has announced
the head official, Jiang Wenqing to be beheaded immediately.
What ... what about the other officials?
I don't know, My Lady.
So ... you came here for Companion An's father, My Lady?
Yes, Companion An was overcome with grief.
I have to do something.
No no no ...
In my view, My Lady, all you can do is stand by.
I hope you will enlighten me, sir.
His Majesty strongly disapproves of
any concubine interfering in state affairs.
This is a great concern for the military,
especially for General Nian Gengyao.
If you speak for Companion An,
isn't that equivalent to offending Consort Fleur?
But this is not about offending anyone.
I cannot just stand and watch
when I can save someone's life.
I'm afraid that is what you will have to do.
Please consider: your father will be lenient as soon as he receives a letter from you;
it makes no difference if His Majesty knows of your involvement or not.
But if someone uses your action
in order to provoke anger in His Majesty,
wouldn't that imperil your father's post?
But what if Companion An's father is not guilty...?
If so, he will be proven innocent after investigation.
You didn't see how furious His Majesty was just now.
It's not worthwhile to risk His Majesty's favor for this matter.
Also, you are now with child and in sight of
the power to assist in palace management,
why would you wade into this muddy water?
And if Her Highness Consort Fleur
hears about your pleading,
Companion An's father will definitely die.
Then ...
- Sir, please don't tell His Majesty that I came.
- Yes.
It is hot out here.
Please go quickly, My Lady.
Don't be sad. We'll think of another way.
What other way?
Even Meizhuang wasn't able to do anything about it.
No one else would be able to.
What Meizhuang said is reasonable.
If she speaks up for you, Consort Fleur
will spare no effort to put your father to death.
But what else can I do?
His Majesty has announced the
immediate execution of Jiang Wenqing today.
Tomorrow ...
it could be my father.
Let's go see the Empress.
The Empress ...
Peace to My Ladies.
May I trouble you to inform Her Majesty
that Companion An and I request an audience?
You've come at an inopportune time, My Ladies.
Her Majesty is not here.
If I recall correctly, this is the time Her Majesty rises from her afternoon nap.
Her Majesty went to see His Majesty
at the Governance Hall.
My Ladies, I believe Her Majesty and you have
endured today's scorching heat for the same reason.
Her Majesty is resourceful.
She anticipated our request and
went to see His Majesty first.
It is uncertain when Her Majesty will be back.
Would you mind waiting in the side chamber?
Tea has been prepared.
Thank you, Madam Autumn.
Please.
The Empress went to the Governance Hall?
What for, in the midday heat?
I learned that Her Majesty was pleading
in favor of An Bihuai, Companion An's father.
You mean, the official who failed to escort the army provisions?
Your Highness's brother, General Nian,
is fighting valiantly on the frontier
while they couldn't do such
a small thing for him at the back end.
No wonder His Majesty was enraged.
Only ...
Is Your Highness going to pay a visit as well
now that the Empress has done Companion An a favor?
Isn't Companion An very close to Lady Sourire and Lady Vertu?
They are like sisters.
No one can be like sisters in the harem.
It's just the weak being reliant on the strong,
and the unintelligent obedient to the wise.
Sisters of today will become tomorrow's nemeses.
A smile on the face is only to hide a dagger in the back.
Your Highness's sharp words "draw blood with one needle."
Do you prefer the harem to be managed
with a velvet glove or an iron fist?
My dull-witted mind knows nothing of such things.
Conflicts occur wherever women gather.
They cry with scheming tears
and smile despite a spiteful mind.
The harem appears as a pond of still water,
but beneath the surface, turbulent currents surge.
Were I to govern the harem,
I would rule with an iron fist and iron heart.
I dare anyone to ignore law and discipline
under the threat of severe punishment.
Your Highness is absolutely right.
Her Majesty the Empress returns.
Peace and grace to Your Majesty.
All rise.
Have a seat.
I thank Your Majesty.
I did all I could to help Companion An's father.
But it isn't up to me.
His Majesty only said that it was a matter in court.
If Your Majesty says so ...
That is all I can do as well.
At this point, we can only count on Heaven's blessings,
and whether His Majesty will be open to further discussion.
Lingrong is most grateful for
Your Majesty's help and consideration.
I will always remember Your Majesty's benevolence.
You may rise.
Misfortune can befall anyone.
I am not only the head of the harem,
but also a sister to all of you in the family.
I must help you whenever my ability allows.
No matter how things turn out,
we are eternally grateful for Your Majesty's words.
Ever since I entered the palace, I have been intimidated
by Consort Fleur's cold and domineering eyes.
Your Majesty is a caring, motherly presence
to the harem and the whole nation.
I ...
Lady Sourire, you are a sensible person.
You must offer some comfort to Companion An.
I share the same gratitude as Companion An
for Your Majesty's care and support.
How may we possibly repay Your Majesty's favor?
There is one trouble after another in the harem,
but my health limits my energy to manage it all.
With a perceptive mind like yours, Lady Sourire,
you can ease some of my worries, if you know what they are.
Aiya,
on such a hot day, the ash in the censer
could flame back up.
What should we do about it?
It is by the grace of Your Majesty
that we can have a peaceful life in the palace.
We therefore must share Your Majesty's burdens.
"While the wise exercises their mind,"
we humble concubines
will take the necessary actions
to return Your Majesty's kindness.
Very well, you did not let me down.
"Under the bright moon and faint stars,
fly the crows to the south afar."
"They encircle a tree for many a time,
finally able to rest upon a branch."
[Duan Ge Xing by Cao Cao]
In sooth, there is only one tree in the harem.
But the bright-colored flowers may deceive your eyes.
All is well as long as you can distinguish the tree from the flowers.
I thank Your Majesty.
I will always remember your advice.
Consort Fleur is aware that the Empress
has seen His Majesty for An Bihuai's case.
Right now, no one is more concerned about
Her Majesty than Consort Fleur.
Take a guess what Consort Fleur is doing.
Presumably, she is doing
the opposite of what Her Majesty did -
pleading with His Majesty to punish An Bihuai severely.
We must thank her if that's the case.
How so, My Lady?
We must thank her for putting in so much effort,
which will save us a lot of trouble.
When did you come in? I wasn't even aware.
Si Lang, you were soundly asleep.
I didn't have the heart to disturb you.
The memorandums are never exhausted before I am.
Before I know it, I have spent the entire day reading.
Those old fogeys never miss a day -
writing to bother me, even over nothing.
It is their duty as the officials.
Si Lang need not be too tough on them.
And with the affectionate ladies visiting to keep you company,
they must have made your work more enjoyable.
It must have been a poetic scene where a
"fragrant red cuff perfumed each turned page."
Hmm, it smells really good.
I've humored your cheeky tongue.
You've grown even brasher.
Compared to Her Highness Consort Fleur,
Huan Huan barely understands Your Majesty.
All I do is upset Si Lang.
How did you know Consort Fleur was here?
The fan is scented with "Celestial Palace,"
a rare rouge that is intricately crafted
with a captivating fragrance.
It's granted to very few in the palace.
Her Majesty eschews perfume,
so it must be Her Highness who came
elegantly dressed to see Your Majesty.
And the scent of her rouge lingers on the fan.
You can "discern a great truth from a small phenomenon."
Si Lang, just tell me if I'm right.
Your nose sees everything.
Consort Fleur set her foot in when the Empress had just left.
They came here for the same person.
Was it for Companion's father, An Bihuai?
Exactly.
What about you?
What brought you here?
Let Huan Huan take a guess.
Her Majesty is kind-hearted.
She must be pleading for Companion An.
Her Highness has a just mind.
She must be in favor of impersonal law enforcement.
What about you?
The harem must not interfere in state affairs.
Huan Huan always bears that in mind.
I'm just curious, since Her Majesty and Her Highness
had opposing views on the same issue,
does that mean their opinions can be reconciled
and the case is worth further examination?
What do you mean?
From my reading of history, the illustrious emperors
tended to punish the primary culprit while showing mercy to the dependents.
This would inspire in the people
not only reverence but also gratitude.
As an admirer of the founding emperors
of the Tang and Song Dynasties,
Your Majesty is a sagacious and benevolent emperor as well.
In my humble opinion,
the reign is bright when outward wars
and inward penalties are clear.
I have known you are well-versed in literature,
but you are also proficient in history and national tactics.
You inform governance in light of history
without direct reference to the state affairs.
I'm grateful to have your assistance,
as if adding a jewel to my crown.
I will have An Bihuai's case re-investigated.
No innocent should be unjustly convicted.
I hope Your Majesty will pardon
my brazen violation of the rules for women.
While the harem cannot interfere in the court,
I am your husband, not your monarch,
when you are alone with me.
From history to political views, you can speak
freely of anything with your husband.
There's nothing wrong with that.
I dare not.
Noble Lady Sourire doesn't dare to,
but Zhen Huan can.
Yes, I dare not overstep my bounds before Your Majesty,
but Huan Huan will talk her heart out to Si Lang.
I'm here to congratulate My Lady!
Thank you, Madam. What happened?
Early this morning, His Majesty ordered Shen Zishan,
the Commander of Jizhou to re-investigate your father's case.
We are hopeful that he will be spared.
Really?
Of course.
The Empress pleaded for the case yesterday, and
His Majesty must give face to Her Majesty.
I thank Her Majesty.
Not now, My Lady. You should thank Her Majesty
in person when all is well with your father.
It seems that Lady Sourire went to see His Majesty as well.
Lady Vertu and Lady Sourire are like sisters to you, My Lady!
Sourire does treat me wholeheartedly
while Meizhuang ...
Lady Vertu has sent a letter to Mr. Shen
to take care of the matter.
Anyone can give a push to the boat
when it's already carried by the current.
In fact, His Majesty was certainly going to
pardon Mr. An as the Empress spoke for you.
If only Lady Vertu had sent the letter sooner,
you wouldn't have to worry so much, My Lady.
I have some errands to run.
Please allow me to take my leave, My Lady.
Take care, Madam.
Coua...
Quickly, collect some valuable jewelry of mine.
My family must have spent a lot of money to buy favors from others.
My mother must be having a hard time
at home if I don't help her.
She suffers from poor eyesight, and
my father's concubines often bully her.
Were if not for my aunt's help,
I can't imagine how much worse it would be for her.
It's fortunate that Lady Sourire has sent you many gifts.
You can select some items and send them home, My Lady.
What is the use of even the finest jewelry?
I have finally learned that no one
carries more weight than the Empress.
Of course, the Empress is the most important woman
in the palace other than the Empress Dowager.
Now I know I can never count on anyone else.
Meizhuang addresses me as her sister,
but in a crisis, stays away from me like a plague.
My Lady, I feel that Lady Sourire is sincere to you.
I know in my heart who is good to me.
My Lady, I think you should rely on
yourself rather than anyone else.
You can gain favor for yourself to "smooth
your furrowed eyebrows" and make your parents proud.
I'm incapable of that, and devoid of a chance to do so.
As long as you have the heart, My Lady,
there will be a way.
Why are you not fanning My Lady inside
when it's so hot right now?
His Majesty is here. I don't dare to stay in.
I'm using a sticky pole to catch the cicadas
so My Lady can have better sleep.
Only catching the cicadas on this tree?
There are many more trees in the outer yard.
It won't be quiet until you catch them all.
Hey, aren't you going to do it with me!
My Lady sent me to collect some lotus flowers
so she could see them after her nap.
I'm going to put them in a vase.
I beg Your Majesty's pardon.
I didn't know Your Majesty was here.
I didn't mean to interrupt.
My Lady, I didn't mean to.
You must be the Jade who likes to wear jade.
Yes, Your Majesty has a good memory.
You may leave after you put away the flowers.
Yes.
Why did you put the flowers in a big bowl?
Your Majesty, I was hoping to keep them floating
in the bowl the same way they're blooming on the lake.
They will look more beautiful.
You have a pretty face and an even more beautiful mind.
I thank Your Majesty.
Even your maid takes after you.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: The Phoenix Taking Flight
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
The dreams I dimly recall;
The past I hardly remember,
amidst the autumn moons and the spring flowers.
Like the moon's reflection on water
or flowers seen through mist - floating and drifting.
The joyous sounds you brought;
The silence you left;
Changing faster than clouds can turn to rain.
Our minds resonated;
Our hearts beat in unison;
But we lost what we once possessed.
A poem to converse;
A melody to accompany;
A heart to bind to mine.
I hoped for endless longing and eternal promise,
but I’m left with only the flute and the zither.
With affection, I pleased;
With my heart, I committed;
With my arms, I embraced.
I desired to be remembered;
Desired to be cherished;
Why am I only hated and deceived?
My wish ran against my will.
Behold the mockery of destiny and the game of fate.
My unwavering love is gone
like flowers swept away in the wind.
Praying for a bright moon;
Praying for a rising sun;
Dreaming to bask in the spring breezes.
But the unsparing northern winds carry snow and rain
to destroy the aspirations of the plum tree.
A phoenix about to take flight rustles its wings
but the arc of its flight is unseen.
The phoenix tree sways in the wind,
shedding memories in the whispers of the falling leaves.